Xavier University Academic Deans meeting records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Academic Deans meeting records
1957-2010
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of the Provost and Chief Academic Officer
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This is a collection of meeting minutes and related materials of the Xavier University Academic Deans.The name of this unofficial group has changed several times over the years.
XUA-20
History of Xavier University Academic Deans meeting group
Historically the Academic Deans of Xavier University have met to discuss issues of common interest. The university Academic Vice President (later the university Provost and Chief Academic Officer) usually called and chaired the meeting.
Since at least 1957, the deans of the colleges and other academic administrators met together regularly, usually under the chairmanship of the Academic Vice President/ Provost. The title of the group varied from time to time. From 1975 to 1987,it was call the "The Council of Deans." From 1987 to 1992 it was known as "The Academic Affairs Advisory Council-Group 1." The Academic Affairs Advisory Council also had a "Group 2" and a "Group 3" which were made up of departmental chairs and other academic officers and which occasionally met with Group 1. From 1993 to 2001 the name was simply "The Deans' Meetings." From 2002 until 2006 it was called "The Academic Council." In 2006 the group became the "Academic Administrative Council." The group of deans was never recognized as a standing committee of the university. Its function was to afford the deans an opportunity to discuss and decide matters of mutual interest.
Scope and Content
This is a collection of minutes and related materials of the Xavier University Academic Deans meetings from 1957 to 2010. There are some gaps in holdings for this period however.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into folders chronologically.
Separated Material
Academic Deans meeting minutes and related materials for 2002-2006 (then called the Academic Council) can be found digitized and stored in the Xavier University Archives permanent retention drive. Please contact the archives staff for details. These minutes are in no way related to the Academic Council which operated in the 1970's and which was the predecessor of the Board of Undergraduate Studies.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Administration; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Planning
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Academic Administrative Council
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1957-1971; 1974- 1983 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1989 June-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1990 July-October (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8 A)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1992 April-August (Box 2, Folder 9 A)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1992 September-December (Box 2, Folder 9 B)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1993 - 1995 May (Box 2, Folder 9 C)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Academic Deans' Meeting Minutes, 2007-2010 (Box 3, Folder 19)